you know the vulnerability that you
submitted that wasn't a vulnerability
that you told other you
told Joel I listen I love the energy
this is viewing very closely into
blackmail it's not blackmail
[Music]
[Applause]
sup y'all if you've listened to critical
thinking for any time at all you know
that we very often cover the asset note
teams research that they put out on
Enterprise security and zero days that
they've been popping left and right um
and lucky for us now the team had no
longer just has a Blog but they've got a
podcast called surfacing security where
they talk about everything Enterprise
security related um in a tax surface
management related and I've I've been
following each episode and just just
listen to these episode titles okay
internet-wide Recon moving past IP
Centric approaches very interesting
Beyond Shadow it understanding the true
attack surface of your software this
one's focused on like thirdparty
softwares and how they can affect your
Enterprise security um posture and the
unknown complexities of DNS resolution
Guys these guys know DNS resolution like
no one I've ever met I've probably spent
10 plus hours just discussing DNS
resolution and their DNS Pipeline with
the Asino team and they know their [__]
inside outside upside down um so if any
of those sound interesting to you check
out the new surfacing security podcast
on the asset note YouTube channel or
wherever you get your podcasts all right
back to the
show come on agree with me a little bit
Joel come
on dude it's pretty solid right pretty
good it's pretty good man shout out to
our boy YT with the new uh Corsair
captain song he dropped on Soundcloud
this week it's pretty pretty good stuff
let's cut let's cut to a longer clip of
it let's
go B up
pull on SW fix [__] I break it I I
patch it all my homies man keep it just
as ratet we will see walk on a CPU a eat
it to spin in your her wonder why we
beating
you should just leave it we should just
leave it like that no no just no Richard
don't do it Richard don't even think
about it um no dude that was that was
great um shout out to YT dude I don't
know if we've given you know we we we've
put um in the show notes every week that
he did our intro like for free very
quickly and I just so appreciated that
and uh and so I just wanted to give a
little extra publicity just a little
little extra publicity to his his new
song it's it's it's a banger for sure
yeah totally some of some of these
lyrics man hold on let me let me find
When the Sun Goes Down is when I'm doing
all that dirty dirty hacking on the
Gibson while I'm chilling with a pretty
girly I love it I think we can all
relate you oh yeah oh yeah solid very
solid stuff there man um all right dude
when I opened up Twitter this week well
first of all first of all for those of
you on on YouTube let me just let me
just Flex this amazing hacker tattoo
that I've got here that I finished up
this week oh yeah looks pretty good
right very nice yeah dude I saw the pic
I was uh I was I was surprised cuz I
knew you T You' said that you were going
to do it but uh I didn't know when and
then you you just you just did it 28
hours under the needle Joel yeah that's
uh well it is a full arm sleeve for so
yeah a forearm yeah I still got I still
got to do the backside here you know
like right here cuz when I'm looking in
the mirror like like check this out you
know when I'm looking like this you
can't even barely see I have anything
behind the beside the band yeah what's
the point of having tattoos if you can't
see them all the time that's what I'm
saying long sleeves I'm done forever
always GNA be rolled up now how long did
it take GNA be the middle of winter
Justin like short sleeve sleeveless
shirt it's like ah this weather oh these
oh these
oh yeah these are my tattoos oh my gosh
I I didn't know you saw them please tell
me I'm not that cring
my dude how long how long did it take
you to do yours because yours is a flash
right yeah mine mine wasn't too bad I
want to say it was like I don't know an
hour and a half or something hour and a
half not bad yeah dude the guy that did
my tattoo um ninjer he he's actually a
hacker as well and he's sort of retired
from from tattooing and uh is is just
doing hacking stuff now but um he's he's
amazing man and he he did it very
in-depth and one of the crazy things
about this is that it doesn't like even
afterwards you know how a lot of times
when you like put the wrap on it or
whatever it will like the ink will like
bleed out and it and it'll like so it
didn't do that at all and I'm like how
did how did you do that and he's like
man I don't know like a lot of tattoo
artists they just like Yeet the ink in
there and I just kind of you know put it
just deep enough and I'm like dang dude
that's that's pretty skilled that's
awesome that's awesome shout out to my
boy ner thanks for the tat man yeah um
all right all right dude now that I've
said my piece with
that I opened Twitter this week and what
do I
see Ron Chan man Ron
Chan you remember our homie he's back
hell yeah I remember him Ron's my man
I'm I'm uh I'm very excited to see him
tweeting some stuff out and he has got a
uh so for for those of you that maybe
aren't familiar because I know he's kind
of jumped in and out of the space a
little bit Ron is an amazingly talented
hacker and and uh and he was in the live
hacking event circuit um for a long time
and uh just really impressed all of us
that were there and now he is back on
the bug Bounty Twitter scene with his
new startup off
zai what do you think man it certainly
seems really interesting he he made a
tweet the other day that was very uh
very accurate I feel like um where it
was basically like you know the idea is
that you know you get enough people
using your tooling that they go oh this
is really interesting say who's making
this tooling and then you you like
contract to the company who's making the
tooling to for like pent tests and that
kind of stuff so um I think like that's
generally the business model and I think
like when you when you when you think
about like tooling like it's not usually
it's something that you're already going
to be creating so it's not necessarily A
Time sync to be creating that tooling
and like Distributing it for marketing
purposes or whatever it's you know it's
helpful for your business and it's help
it's something that you're already
planning on using so um kind of just
like stream streamlines your process as
business and then also gives you
opportunities to flex sort of your your
capabilities so yeah I think it's really
cool I like it I I I think so too and I
think it's a good it's a good
application of AI right this whole
permission you know off of Z permission
scheme thing like I feel like that's
pretty ingestible into Ai and then a lot
of what makes that difficult to test for
is something that an AI could actually
you know wrap their head around pretty
easily I think um I I I'm interested to
see what what the sort of um ingestion
process for this whole thing is is is
going to look like um you know and he
said he's found some some some bugs with
it already and um but just the whole the
whole like you have a I feel like it'd
be really amazing if you could just like
somehow provide a screenshot of like the
permission Matrix or whatever and and
somehow like a multimodal AI would would
grab the data out of there synthesize it
into a format that that this can can
deal with and see what it can find yeah
for sure Ian it seems like looking at
the the repo for this it seems like you
give it somewhat of like an open API ask
description um of sort of like how your
API works in the off uh around it and
all that kind of stuff and then it will
do the analysis so it's uh it seems
really really cool and I'm excited to
see what what other stuff that Ron's
going to be creating because he's super
smart and talented and always has lots
of good ideas yeah yeah dude this is
definitely a a cool intro I'm surprised
he you know I'm a little on on one hand
I'm a little surprised that this is open
source I and I think like you said you
know it plays to the business model of
like you know we'll open source this and
it will and it will convert into um
business for for for the actual um
consultancy but um yeah I feel like the
AI stuff right now it's pretty it's
pretty hot to like make it into a
service or something like that that you
can use and uh and but he decided to
open source it so solid solid yeah yeah
absolutely it'll be really interesting
to to see I'm still not sure how I feel
about the whole AI bubble thing like I
think it's it's definitely cooled down a
lot um so we'll we'll see what happens
like I think you know as with any new
technology there was sort of that like
explosion of new startups and ideas and
Concepts and all this wow factor stuff
and now it's it's sort of chilled down a
little bit to some of the more practical
realistic implementations of it yeah um
so yeah I I think it'll be really
interesting to see uh how this
progresses H have you played around much
with A1 preview and like the the whole
thinking stuff behind yeah I use that as
like whenever I'm doing anything that's
like not service level like you know
reinterpretation of data or whatever
like if it's if I wanted to actually
like give me something that I'm more
confident about the results I I use o
one okay solid yeah that makes sense we
just an anecdotal experience but um you
know Mariah and I play volleyball and uh
and Mariah's team captain and she's
responsible for doing the rosters right
you know and like putting people at
their various spots on the on the uh on
the field or whatever on the court and
um she tried to give it to chat GPT
sometimes she' be like all right this
person works well with this person and
like this is our Setter and you know and
just describe it all and before it just
totally failed uh like it was putting
we play coed right so it has to be guy
girl guy girl guy girl um and it was
putting guys next to guys and it was
like it was it was a mess so I I'm I'm
interested to see if the uh 01 preview
can do a little bit better on some of
those more technical tasks and my I I
think it probably will it probably will
because like you know the whole thinking
thing is basically just like using the
AI to check the AI right where it like
it'll output something and I think the
natural thought for us is like if it
gets us wrong why like why do I as a
human have to be like no you're wrong
and then it'll be like oh yeah you're
right I am wrong like it should just do
that on its own and so that's kind of
what it's doing where it it it'll look
retroactively back and be like here's
what I output does that make sense did
did you do the thing right no I didn't
it'll be like it'll be like actually
actually that that doesn't really make
sense so I'm gonna redo it so so I you
know it's very sort of natural like way
of going about it I think so um yeah
I've definitely seen I think the
somebody told me the stats were like
that on like the programming uh
questionnaire or whatever like when they
fed it into the 40 um it was I think it
was
like 20% or something or 50% or
something it got through and then when
they gave it to 01 it was like 80% so it
was pretty good dang I I also feel like
um a lot of the problems that it fails
on it could output code to solve you
know like like if I say output code that
calculates the possible iterations of
this team's like volleyball structure
then it I think it would be able to do
that pretty well but then you know if
you just ask it to do it then it's like
well hold up like yeah so yeah yeah it
um and and I think what you'll notice is
if you click it if you expand stuff this
has happened for a while but like C cat
gbt as a whole uses code to do a lot of
what it does so if you're like um look
at this picture and tell me what's going
on it will write a python script that
ocrs it and then it will run that and
then it will run that python script and
if you expand like what it's like
thinking about or whatever it'll it'll
literally just be like writing a python
script oh that's cool that's like the
code interpreter thing is that is that
that no no this is just like normal like
if you ask it to do more complex Tas it
will end up just writing a a piece of
code that does that task and running
that code well of course Chad gbt
thought of that that makes sense I
didn't just come up with this crazy idea
to like that all these genius people
over at open AI
uh didn't come up with um all right cool
well we got a little little derail there
but um let's let's swing back around to
this blog post that we wanted to cover
this week um on ofon security from our
boy Roan um and he dude I love how Roan
always goes after the very Fringe parts
of a company like you never see Roan
just like yeah here's an idor on dubdub
dub you know like like he's he's always
hitting like the ticket system the live
chat system that sort of thing and I
think this one this one turned out
pretty impactfully for him yeah yeah
absolutely um he's always doing really
cool stuff uh I used to work with Roan
and uh I was really excited to hear that
he was going to start this this uh the
security company and uh the stuff that
they've been doing lately in terms of
like research and stuff is really really
awesome so um to see doing doing quality
research and then you know using that to
to as lead gen for your I mean it's it's
like you know what better way to show
that like you know you you're capable
you have capable security Folks by other
than doing actual security research I
mean think back to even just how like
hacker one started like hacker one's
whole business model originally was hack
these companies give them bug reports
and be like hey do you want to start a
bug bending
program yeah so yeah I think that that
sort of like uh you know uh results by
example type stuff is really really good
yeah yeah I I I thought you were going
to go with the cake story for for hacker
one have you heard the hacker one cake
story The Cake story I think
I'm so I I think I was talking to ybert
or or maybe it was one of the other
Founders at a Live Hack he me but he was
he was pretty much saying like in the
beginning one of the ways they would say
you know one of the ways they would get
customers or whatever was like Hey if we
can't hack you we'll buy your whole
office of cake and and and then they you
know they always hacked them so it's
fine you know but uh but this just a low
risk yeah
but I mean somebody walks in your office
trade offer we hack you or we send you a
cake that's pretty good I liked that
though Innovative marketing you know
yeah yeah um I'm gonna go ahead and let
me just go ahead and share my screen
because uh our I met with our video
editor yesterday and he said that I
should share my screen more so that you
guys can get some stuff on the uh uh
like some visuals or whatever um okay so
this is the write up from from Roan here
and ofon security and I I thought this
was a pretty insightful little little
graphic here um I don't know if it's big
enough to see but if not we'll we'll
make it it visible but um essentially it
explains the flow for how some of these
live chat authentication systems work
and um it starts off with uh you know
the user coming to your website and
essentially on the back end it generates
an hmac digest using the user's
identifiers in secret key dumps it back
and then passes that to you you know in
this example help shift uh but in in
other scenarios other live chat Services
he said this was a you know a trend he
saw across a couple of them and then
that's what is used for authentication
um so it's a it's a pretty it's a pretty
uh you know reasonable flow um the
problem with that is that you're you're
leaving a lot of this authentication up
to the end user um so what we see from
the example that he dropped here is uh
that they were just using thisor svpt
cookie with an email address value in it
um and it was just dumping back the uh
the actual you know You' put the email
address in there and it' dump back the
off token um and so you know when we're
trusting when we're trusting that end
user there or the end um user of the the
live chat software um to to deal with
that correctly there's definitely some
room some room for error especially on
these systems that sort of get I guess
duct taped into the whole flow um you
know and that really goes back to what
ASO team was just talking about a couple
weeks ago on their on their surfacing
security podcast for like these
thirdparty softwares that are taped into
your main app are often the weakest
Point um so I feel like I often Overlook
these especially when it's something
like this where it's like oh I needed to
weed out all of the cookies to find that
just thisor svpt cookie was what was
handling off yeah yeah exactly yeah I
mean I think those integration points
are super super important because
it's made to be easy
but that often means that assumptions
have to be made to make it easy yeah
yeah I I think so too so I'm definitely
going to make sure I look at these I've
also recently found a uh a vulnerability
in the live chat system that affected
like dubdub duub and was pretty gnarly
um so I feel like this might be a
surface that a lot of people look at and
be like third party stuff I'm not sure
I'm going to touch that you know it's
probably used on a lot site but I think
it's also an attack surface for a good
amount of um like if you get a zero day
on it there's a lot of impact that can
be sprayed across a lot of companies um
right and and so that's uh that's a good
place for research I think this is
pretty topical I guess CU here we
go hacking third parties yep yeah
speaking of hacking third parties and
affecting other companies right so
there's this whole zenes thing um so
yeah why don't we why don't we talk
about that okay all right we're opening
up can of worms a little bit here um
yeah dude I don't know I mean this is
the main topic for this week right like
and and I I kind of wish that we had
jumped on it a little bit more when it
was fresh right um but I think we'll
just I just wanted to at least mention
it and and debate it a little bit here
because I think there's a lot of nuance
to this situation but the principles
apply pretty broadly um and for those of
you that aren't familiar with the the
what I'm entitling the zenes f go
uh there's there was a a 15-year-old
researcher clearly very skilled that uh
found a way to let's just say pone zenes
right it was it it was regarding the
email system and being able to leak the
contents of any help desk ticket um and
they reported to zenes and because it
has some of those like keyword
indicators right like um the what what
was the actual one like the email
security headers sping yeah email
spoofing right um you know 99% of the
vulnerabilities that you get through
your bu Bounty program that contain
email spoofing are going to be
informative or na right um but this one
was valid and the team ended up closing
it as informative um and the the
researcher was like of course okay well
you know if it's not a bug then I guess
I need to tell other companies about
this because I think there's risk and
maybe they will think of that too and
then it just started raising a bunch of
problems for Zen desk because all the
third parties were like whoa whoa whoa
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa how did
you how did you leak all of our internal
ticket data and then zenes was happen to
deal with a fire on their hands um right
so I don't know Joel I know you have a
little bit more program side experience
than me so maybe there's some some
Nuance to the situation I'm missing but
it seems like a pretty clear misstep by
zenes to me yeah so I mean generally it
seems like this entire thing was a
pretty bad miscommunication between
parties like I don't know if zenes uses
um H1 triage um I don't know if that was
disclosed in
the um in the write
up H1 they do yeah so H1 analyst yeah
Leila was the one that so so triage
triage screwed this up like they you
know they said okay this is email
spoofing so it didn't even reach the
customer team essentially at that at
that point right and
then
they I believe hack the research Richard
did mediation mhm and
then mediation also
said this is spoofing this is email
spoofing so it's not going to count yeah
um and
then at that point like I don't think
like I understand the research or
thought process of like oh maybe other
companies want to hear about this so
like it's been marked as like not an
issue by the program so I'm going to
like I'm free to report this M I don't
know about that one like maybe
like yeah what is the correct route for
the researcher going forward then I
wonder like if if you've been if you
went through the the mediation process
if you've tried to get your your report
relooked at and and they won't do it um
you know what recourse does the
researcher have at that point I wonder I
mean I don't know if they necessarily do
have recourse I think
like the fact that they went around
zenes afterwards and it happened that
companies agreed that they cared about
it from an impact perspective I think is
kind of to be honest more of a luck sort
of situation thing than anything like
realistically the fact that zenes didn't
think it was something that need to be
fixed in the beginning also
well I'm assuming that they had to have
that discussion at some point because
when you go through mediation like
you're getting get reached out to
directly so so they definitely had to
review it at some point like oh yeah
it's unlikely mediation that is the case
yeah like I've it would be highly
unlikely that like the mediation case
would have been closed um without any
interaction from the zenes team at all
so they probably had to view it and be
like yeah okay this is not something
that we're going to accept um and like
the fact that other companies who had
Zend us were like actually okay this is
something we want to fix and ended up
falling sort of Upstream back to zendesk
like
I think that doesn't always happen like
you'll definitely find cases where
companies will be like uh you know even
if it is something they do care about
they'll be like well how are we supposed
to fix this like there should be a fix
from zenes like if there's no fix from
zenes
then you know do we need to report to
zenes or like you know and then like as
a program manager I'd be like well is
this a zero day like we should be
reporting this as zendesk before it
comes to me right so um I don't know I I
I think like it all sort of falls back
to that initial
case of like zenes being like no this
this is out of scope for the
program um yeah and then when it started
coming back in through through you know
the customer channels zenes should have
reopened the report and said you know we
are actually going to fix this and just
they could have handled it that way and
it would have been very easy I think
going the route of you know you violated
our program terms by reporting this to
other companies and stuff like
not something I would have done okay wow
that that's that's an interesting
approach to it I think I think um I
think for me where where the buck Falls
there is that when it was closed as
informative and the mediation process
ended I feel like the hacker doesn't
have any other recourse at that point
besides reporting it to other to other
programs um well it's more so there's
this whole concept of um implicit
agreement right um where I think a lot
of researchers like they they kind of
like to try and ignore this or like
think that it doesn't exist from but
from a program side it's like basically
the only like agreement you have with
the researcher which is that when you
submit something to a program you're
agreeing to the program's policy and
terms and that you know you're not going
to disclose the details of the
vulnerability without the permission of
the program and all that kind of stuff
like by submitting it which is why when
you know if you want to do it disclosure
after 90 days you should never report it
through a BG program you should submit
it to their email right like and I think
that's I don't think that's like
groundbreaking knowledge or anything but
but like that is really the lens that
you need to look look at it through
which is that like you submitted it to
the program which means you're now in
like a a semi- binding agreement with
that program about you know that
vulnerability and you can't then go turn
around and disclose it to other
companies without the permission of you
know that that program or what like you
know it there are certain things and
it's not a vulnerability though at that
point right like if there if they're
saying informative or na then why why is
this bind and I think this might be and
this might be where the rubber hits the
road here this might be an H1 problem
with regards to terms and services right
because I I think um like the there
should be something that says hey if a
report is informative or na then this is
not something that the the program is
actively but then you get into those
scenarios where it's like you close
something as informative because it's
out of scope but it's actually a valid
vul you know I don't know right yeah
yeah so I
mean I it's definitely a little bit on
on both like again like H1 triage was
the ones who kind of screwed this up
initially and and then H1 mediation as
well like pushed again like from if I
was managing the zenes program and I
look through this and I'm seeing all the
backlash I would have reached out to
Aron and been like hey what's going on
here like I think we probably should
have accepted this why was this decided
as email spoofing twice now
um and you know it just like in terms of
like the um the agreement stuff like the
policy stuff I I view hacker one in the
programs as sort of like uh similar to
like the US like federal and state
system right so like hacker one is like
the federal government in the sense that
that they set overarching policies and
rules and stuff but the programs
themselves can overwrite those just like
states can so in that sense like a
program can say like we we don't follow
the program guide like the platform
standards of XYZ this is how we handle
it instead you're allowed to do that um
so I think you know zenes like on one
hand hacker one can say like and they
probably do you're not allowed to report
or disclose vulnerabilities you know
without permission from the program uh
and you know you'd be violating that on
the hacker one side and zenes also could
and I think they actually do me Lu yeah
in the
response yeah so so in zendesk's policy
here we go share share the details uh
reporting share the details of any
suspected vulnerabilities with the zenes
security team by filing a report please
do not publicly disclose these details
outside of this process with explicit
permission right so the publicly keyword
there you know we could go back on that
but I think like really what it comes
down to is you're not supposed to
disclose details of vulnerability
without exposive permission from the
security team with anybody uh in any in
any format right like whether that's
sharing it with your friend or sharing
it with a company who's affected or
sharing it publicly on a Blog um you
know I think like the pro the program
team went and they said you know we're
not going to fix this so the researcher
to cover their ass they probably should
have just comment and said hey uh is it
all right if I report this to the to
companies who are affected to see if
they want to fix it they disagree yeah
and you know if they say no then it's
like okay well why not why aren't you
going to fix it that that's like a
separate discussion but I
think you know if it's like either you
fix it or you allow them to to disclose
it to the affect the companies and see
if it wants to be fixed and I think the
thing is as well we we didn't actually
see the the full details of the report
that that um this hacker hacker mandev
sent into the zenes program and you know
I'd like to believe that that report was
very detailed in showing impact and
stuff like that um but I know that this
is a tricky situation for a hacker one
right like like it looks like an email
spoofing vulnerability um given the
given the uh nature of zenes and how
many vulnerabilities there have been
relating to email bugs with with zenes I
would I would hope that there would be
something um you know in writing for the
triers that are working on that program
saying hey email related bugs should
take a you know we should take an extra
look at those on this program because
there's been some scary [__] that's
happened you know because of that um
yeah but it is Poss to give the the
program the benefit of the doubt it is
possible that the hacker didn't show
excellent impact the problem is his
writeup was really good and and uh and
so I really don't think that's the case
Cas um and and and so I I definitely
think there wasn't a lot of recourse for
him and if I were in if I were in his
shoes I probably would have done the
same thing and I I went to go and look
at that Hacker's profile by the way and
um he's got like 3,000 rep on on hacker
one so it's not like in a 6.4 signal
right so I feel like I feel like this is
a misstep not by hacker one like it's
not like he's a fresh account you know
first report is like email spoofing
let's go you know it he's got to
establish CU I don't even think you can
do mediation if you have right no signal
right like there are certain limit like
yeah I don't know I I I again I I think
as a whole like there were multiple
missteps in terms of communication and
process here
and I'm going to hold my tongue here a
little bit in terms of my real feelings
but uh you know I will say like I think
this is a systemic problem with all
triage
Services where trying to put a generic
puzzle piece into a complex solution
tends to fail at scale yeah right um and
that generic puzzle piece is triage and
the complex puzzle is a per program
vulnerability validation
solution and when you start having a
team of people whose job is to just
validate vulnerabilities it becomes less
and less
about uh
nuance and context to the program and
how to handle specific vulnerabilities
for specific programs and more about is
this valid yes or no
checkbox binary one zero yeah and is it
reproducible yes you know does it fall
into these categories in the policy that
are out of scope yes or not right and it
becomes a lot more difficult to make
those Nuance decisions at scale so they
don't yeah and then you have these
problems that's the nature of the Beast
and I would have liked to see um hacker
one and maybe they did and I missed it
but I I haven't seen it you know send
out some sort of PR um you know
statement on this specific incident
because it did get a lot of a lot of
press yeah um and and I would have liked
to see them take responsibility for it
because at the end of the day we can see
clearly from the write up that um you
know the first triager closing it as as
informative and then the mediation team
not
fully validating it um was a misstep and
and I think there's a lot of Grace right
because it does have that weird you know
like ah this is probably not an issue
vibe to it but when you look deeper it
does right so if if hacker one had come
out and said hey our bad you know just
want to publicly apologize to hacker Mev
and um and say like hey we we we messed
up that one you know I feel like the
most of the community would be like yeah
we get it man email bugs all right you
know like
yeah I I think like probably the reason
that they're kind of just doing
non-action here is that
um hamand
Dev did fine yeah yeah like he he made
he made plenty of rep plenty of money
plenty of whatever from this his stats
are fine like it there was one like the
root cause instance of this went poly
but like the overall
outcomes fine like what like they're not
going to pull into the make it right
fund for this like he made plenty of
money like so it's it's kind of a tricky
situation like in terms of process yeah
they they definitely could have done
better uh that is something I would be
interested in seeing is some sort of
statement about you know like if there
was a process failure here and whether
or not triage should have said Yep this
is Spam and whether or not mediation
should have also said Yep this is spam
email spam and or email spoofing um and
you know just like a some clarity on
that I think would be good uh just to
know whether or not that's what actually
went wrong or whether it was you know
just a Mis communication or whatever um
but otherwise like you know they're not
going to they don't have anything to
really make right in terms of you know
because again it's like there were
multiple reports that got resolved got
paid out all that kind of stuff on the
affected companies and it's just this
one that was like what informative like
like not even an impact to it yeah I I I
think I think um ngi just in sort of uh
agreement with what you're saying ngi
had a a great reply to one of my tweets
it says he was very fortunate that zenes
initially closed this as informative
otherwise he would have made 1K Max
instead of 50 exactly that's no that's
exactly right yeah yeah and and and I
see that I see that you know um I I
think that's I think that's valid I'm
not trying to minimize the outrage
because I think like again it it it
certainly seems from the outset that
like there was process problem that
something went wrong and you know maybe
there needs to be more clarity about
maybe there needs to be a specific call
out for the triage team doing Zend us
stuff or what like I don't know whatever
needs to happen but like does feel like
something going a little wacky there
that being said yeah exactly what Nagal
said like one one report closes
informative he 50k in b instead right so
yeah you know could be worse it work it
works out in the end um yeah I I did
reach out to H1 and and say like hey do
do any of you guys want to like come on
the Pod and talk about this scenario
because it did blow up a lot and none of
them none of them took me up on it um so
we'll see we'll see if they if they send
out a statement at some point but at the
end of the day I I do sort of agree with
with what you're saying here which is
and what ngi said as well which is that
uh in the end it worked out better for
him guess PR team is hard at work still
yeah well I think he also got a lot of
good PR out of it too you know like he's
he's our he's our boy now like if I see
this y old dude I'm going to be like Su
dude like yeah zenes really screwed you
on that one didn't they um but but I
also think that that um the the response
was not great from the zenes team either
like I feel like at the end of the day
zenes see so this this is what this is
what gets me a little riled up Joel okay
like I I get hack one making mistakes
and not taking responsibility for it I
get it it's a big company now whatever
it's not our our little baby like it
used to be back in you know 2017 or
whatever but um
like I I I think the zenes team should
have done something differently here
because at the end of the day clearly
once they get hit by a bunch of
customers saying hey fix this hey fix
this hey fix this now they know it's a
problem and they go back to this report
and they have the audacity to say to
this to this kid hey uh you shouldn't
have disclosed this even though we you
know the process failed you and you know
even though we overlooked this report
and said this isn't a valid
vulnerability and so they say hey the
researcher did something ethically wrong
and I don't think that's the
case yeah I mean I I agree that that
that Al again yeah as I said I wouldn't
have handled it that way yeah going back
and saying like ah you broke our
policy like yeah nobody literally nobody
would have found out about this if you
just were like
sorry we [__] up exactly here here's a
here's a 3K Bounty yeah resolved dude
then he would have been excited this
would have been great for the zenes team
right you know that would have been
great please stop reporting it to other
customers you like yeah I don't know I
feel like whatever again not how I would
have handled the situation it is what it
is I think there are valuable lessons
that have probably been learned from all
all parties involved um you know from
the researchers side like you're just
because a program closes something as
informative or whatever that you're not
immune right like you still agreed to
program terms you still submitted it to
them that vulnerability still falls
under the guidelines of the program and
the platform and everything and you
can't just you're not just off the hook
because they said n this isn't something
that we're going to fix yeah right um
yeah and from the and from the program
side like if you're getting a lot of
push back about
something give it a little manual look
and um from the platform side like or
just learn how to say you're wrong right
like like that's that's the thing that a
lot of not easy but yeah I mean these
companies and their companies or
whatever and you know people's careers
are probably you know
Gonna Take a Hit or whatever here so
maybe it's a little bit easier for me
said on the outside where my my mistakes
are you know saying something stupid to
my wife versus you know screwing some
hacker out of some money but in a big PR
scenario but I feel like it's not that
hard to say hey sorry about that you
know that was my bad um and that's just
kind of what I would have expected and
now everybody hates the Zenex program
now you know like that that g that gist
had like uh gist gist I we're not going
to start that um had like you know a ton
of comments underneath it being like
what is wrong with you guys like wow
this response is garbage you know um so
I I I think in the end of the day it
really didn't pan out well for for
zendesk and I what Jo
also they left a comment on the [__]
GitHub yeah
I yeah I know you're trying your best to
to be come on let it let it fly a little
bit here Joel come on let your true
thoughts fly I think zendesk needs to
get the pr team that hack one has
yeah cuz interesting it does genius to
be like hm maybe we shouldn't engage
publicly on this like when has that ever
panned out well are you kidding me like
what like you literally like there was a
public forum where people were
commenting and like [__] on you and
then you were like hm I know let's
engage directly and like commented on it
like and then they started getting added
by all these people being like no you're
wrong like oh man way to stoke the fire
I don't know this uh just really uh I
don't know I um it definitely feels like
the security team is on damage control
here not the pr team yeah yeah I agree
okay let me let me run this last thing
by you okay so when I was reading this
and I was all all riled up and I was mad
for my boy hacker mandev here my
15-year-old lead hacker um I was
thinking I feel like zenes needs to be
punished for this behavior um and and
I'm thinking it would be interesting to
have a list of programs that have
notably treated hackers in a way that
doesn't make any sense yeah this is
really interesting coming from you um
because because in like the first two
weeks of us starting our Discord there
was a very similar idea that was floated
and they're like what if we have like a
reputation list of like bad experiences
with program and we were like no this is
a terrible idea because it's literally
just to create a Witch Hunt spreadsheet
where people are going to be like I had
a bad experience with this program and
then nobody's ever going to hack on it
even if the program like management
changes or policies change or anything
it's just like my idea
hasur no no no it's matured and I I
appreciate you being here to to tell me
I'm crazy but I'm crazy and that's fine
you know I I appreciate that that being
said the idea has evolved a little bit
okay so this is only this is a list that
is maintained by us so that will be a
little bit of logistical overhead but um
there will be only hackers of certain
reputation can make submissions to this
list hackers that have successfully
interacted with programs time and time
again and and aren't like just tilty
because they got you know hecked up on
one program or something like that and
it would also have to come along with a
historical reference for the behaviors
that they that they exhibited that are
negative towards researchers and a
remediation
step that the the company can do to get
their their program removed from this
list and like for example in this
scenario if zenes just paid the Bounty
and said sorry about that then we
everything would be fine okay but some
of that is a POS like now what is zenes
supposed to do to get off that list
they're supposed to say so we put up the
you know's let's say zenes was a was a
uh you know an entry on the list we'd
say hey this scenario was really poor
handled and then they they engaged the
hacker and they said hey you you know
the vulnerability that you submitted
that wasn't a vulnerability that you
told other you told this
is I listen I love the energy this is
viewing very closely into blackmail it's
not blackmail it's caring you're just
say you're you're saying we we're
putting you on our bad program list and
if you want to get off the Bad program
list you have to do what we said I'm
just I'm just saying like I think that
is did I just did I just
blackmail I mean I I I think so I don't
know okay all right well thanks for the
thanks for the fact te it's just an idea
and I think that it would provide some
accountability for programs that are
mistreating hackers and we know that
there are programs out there that
mistreat hackers and you and I both know
that we have these disc and and and
people say hey guys don't hack on this
program because they did XYZ and then
everyone's like thanks bro I would never
hack on a program that does that thanks
for the heads up so why don't we just
formalize that um well so what I'll say
is besides the blackmail component which
yeah what what I'll say is like I think
I've had plenty of those experiences
myself but for every one of those
there's there's also an experience where
it's like oh and I had this really bad
experience with this program and the
person I'm talking to goes really I've
never had a bad experience with that
program right and that happens pretty
frequently as well yeah um so so there's
that side of it and the other side is I
think it would probably be better
handled by like an independent third
party where like I I think the general
idea here is that like not the
independent third party no because we're
we have conflict of interest I think
like the idea is is mistreatment of
hackers uh that that definitely happens
right um and so I think probably the
best way to go about that is either the
platforms have some sort of fre platform
either either the platform has like an
audit committee committee some kind
where you know a hacker can say like I
feel like I'm being mistreated by this
program here and it's somewhat of like a
legal system right where like they
submit a case and they they make you
know here's my evidence or whatever and
and the program can can defend it I
think it's something that could get out
of hand right so that that needs to be
handled somehow where like you know if
you have a bunch of hackers who get mad
at a program or whatever or like this
program can't be spending a bunch of
their time like
debating or arbitrating or whatever in
the in The Hacker Court like about well
they're not they're mistreating
hackers
yeah but uh you know I think like some
sort of an independent committee or
process is probably a better strategy
where like you know from like a systemic
level where where you're talking about
where like uh a program is is treating
hackers poorly time and time again on
multiple instances in similar ways then
that can be you know addressed from sort
of like a platform side where the
platform goes hey like you know if you
want to stay on the on hacker one then
you need to uh either change your
policies or yeah I mean or or we could
have I mean at the end of the day you're
right I I I think probably that list is
not the best idea and I think this is
best handled at the platform level and
it would be cool if there was an
independent third party like hacker.com
whoever owns that like let's go um where
where um there some accountability for
that but if the platforms
themselves take responsibility for the
the way that these programs are are
running then then we won't have that
problem so I think that there could be a
world in which we have a petition system
or something like that where if the
community says hey guys this is this is
messed up H1 you need to review this you
need to have some stance on this and we
get you know a thousand signatures on it
whatever then hacker one's like all
right look we we'll we'll we'll take it
under we'll have a statement that sort
of thing yeah I mean maybe the strategy
is like maybe not a petition system
because again this can all be like
Community like you can rally people and
it gets unfair and then you can force
things to Happ but like I think maybe
like an anonymous like review like I
think this program is caus causing
problems unjustly and once they hit a
certain threshold of reports of that
nature then they there's an
investigation that happens like by a
human not just
yeah maybe but and and maybe this does
exist internally at hacker one who knows
but it would be great it would be great
if the the hackers had a little bit more
introspection into this progress or into
this process and I think also this is
this also All Rolls back to the thing
we've been talking about for forever
which is hacker unionization and I think
that this is something that would be
shut up Joel this is a real this is a
real conversation okay this is something
that would
under that perview right and and I don't
think it's going to happen I don't think
it's necessary
but this is something that hackers are
going to
strike well that's a good point where's
our
leverage yeah well I think there's a lot
of
contractors yeah but at the end of the
day you know there's there's you know
billions of dollars in companies uh that
are associated with hackers doing what
they they do so we do have leverage on
the platforms we don't have as much
leverage on the programs but we do have
leverage on the on the platforms if we
say Hey listen we're not going to hack
on hacker one until this until this
stops uh then I think we are at a pretty
leveraged point we are the
product yeah we don't pay any
bills yeah but but the platforms AR or
the programs aren't going to stay on the
platform if if there's no hackers
hacking on the platform right I mean
they can't just up and leave yeah
they've got like
whatever yeah so it'd have to be an
extended thing is what you're saying
yeah it would have to be like minimum
probably six months to a year
yeah makes sense dude makes sense all
right maybe I should giv you ideas no no
thanks for thanks for the uh thanks for
the for the uh you know sanity Tech here
thanks for holding me down man I
appreciate that um I think that's a wrap
you got anything else no I think that's
it all right GG peace all right
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there
oh